outreach.io 2017-09-06

# Privacy Policy - Outreach

### Last modified: March 2, 2017

**Some Notes On Our Relationship**

This Privacy Statement applies to "www.outreach.io" owned and operated by ComponentLab, Inc. doing business as "Outreach". At Outreach, we are committed to maintaining the confidentiality and security of any personal information about our users. Your privacy is always at the top of our priorities, and we are focused on protecting it from unauthorized access.

This Privacy Policy supplements our End User License Agreement (EULA)/Terms of Service and spells out how we collect, use, and disclose of information from or about you through our website www.outreach.io and the Outreach service. Users can access the Outreach service (the "Service") via our website www.Outreach.io, applications on Devices, APIs, and third-parties. A "Device" is any device used to access the Outreach Service, including without limitation a computer, mobile phone, tablet, or other electronic device. By using our Service, you are consenting to the collection, transfer, processing, storage, disclosure and other uses described in this Privacy Policy. The use of information collected through our service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the Outreach client ("Client") has engaged Outreach.

Outreach participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Outreach is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the [U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list).

Outreach is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Outreach complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Outreach is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Outreach may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the [Privacy Shield website](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint), you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted. 

**The Information We Collect and Store**

Outreach employees are prohibited from viewing the content of the data you import into your Outreach account, except as provided in this Privacy Policy. Of course, in the case that you request our help to resolve your support issues relating to that data, and only after receiving your permission, Outreach employees may access the relevant data.

We may collect and store the following information when running the Outreach Service: 

Information You provide. When you register for an account, we collect some personal information, such as your name, phone number, email address, and home and/or business postal addresses. You may also ask us to import your contacts and email history by giving us access to your third party services (for example, your email account) or to use your social networking information if you give us access to your account on social network connection services. In fact, in order to use our Service, you must link a third party email account to your Outreach account. We then import, create, and update versions of your address book and emails for you to access in Outreach. You will also have the option to import and update versions of your calendar, social media contacts, and mobile phone call history, and you can later choose to upload files to, or provide comments through, Outreach. When you invite others to join Outreach by using the Service, we send them an email for that invitation at the email addresses assigned to them in your address book.

**Collection and Use of 3rd Party Personal Information**

You may also provide personal information about other people, such as their email address. This information is only used for the sole purpose of completing your request or for whatever reason it may have been provided. If you believe that one of your contacts has provided us with your personal information and you would like to request that it be removed from our database, please contact us at [support@outreach.io](mailto:support@outreach.io).

**Your Data and Other Information About You**

With your permission (which you grant when you sign up for or begin using our Service), Outreach collects and stores information you provide or that we collect in order to administer our Services and/or as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy or our Terms of Service. If you or another user uploads a file to Outreach that has been previously uploaded by you or another user, we may associate all or a portion of the previous file with the applicable accounts rather than storing duplicates.

**User Data Supplementation**

We may receive additional demographic information about you from other sources, including publicly available databases or third parties from whom we have purchased data, and combine this data with information we already have about you. This helps us to update, expand and analyze our records, identify new customers, and provide products and services that may be of interest to you. If you provide us personal information about others, or if others give us your information, we will only use that information for the specific reason for which it was provided to us.

Outreach obtains this business contact and company information from third party sources, such as business intelligence platforms. The information obtained by these third-party sources is from publicly available sources such as news articles. This information is used to support Outreach’s marketing and sales efforts. The Outreach sales team may contact you based on this information to gauge your company’s interest in Outreach’s services and technology solutions. You may opt-out of these communications at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link provided in the email or by sending a request to the Outreach Technical Support team by emailing [support@outreach.io](mailto:support@outreach.io). 

**Log Data**

When you use the Service, we automatically collect certain information from your Device, its software, and your activity using the Services. This may include, for example (but without limitation), the Device's Internet Protocol ("IP") address, browser type, the web page visited before or after you came to our website, information you search for on our website, locale preferences, identification numbers associated with your Devices, your mobile carrier, date and time stamps associated with transactions, system configuration information, metadata, and interactions with the Service, Internet service provier, referring/exit pages, the files viewed on our site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data to analyze trends in the aggregate and administer the site. 

**Cookies**

Outreach and its partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our website or service.

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this website and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

**Social Media Widgets/Buttons**

Our website includes social media features, such as the Facebook Like button and widgets, such as the "Share This" button for Twitter and LinkedIn. These features may collect your IP address and the page you are visiting on our site, and they may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**How We Use Personal Information**

In the course of using the Service, we may collect or otherwise obtain information that can be used to contact or identify you ("Personal Information"). Personal Information is or may be used: (i) to provide and improve our Service, (ii) to administer your use of the Service, (iii) to recommend follow-up reminders, assign tasks, or personalize the service, and (iv) to provide or offer software updates and product announcements. If you no longer wish to receive communications from us that are not required for the Service, please follow the "unsubscribe" instructions provided in any of those communications, or update your account settings information.

**Information Sharing and Disclosure by Us No Sale of Personal Information**

We do not sell Personal Information to third parties.

**Service Providers, Business Partners and Others**

We may use certain trusted third-party companies and individuals to help us provide, analyze, and improve the Service (including but not limited to data storage, maintenance services, database management, web analytics, payment processing, and improvement of the Service's features). These third parties may have access to your information for purposes of performing these tasks on our behalf and under obligations similar to those in this Privacy Policy. As of the date this policy went into effect, we use Amazon's S3 storage service to store some of your information (for example, your files). You can find more information on Amazon's data security from the S3 site.

**Third-Party Applications**

Our website includes links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Outreach. As of the date this policy went into effect, Outreach has never and will not share your information with a third-party application. If you submit personal information to any of those websites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. In the future, with your consent, we may share your information with a third-party application (for example when you choose to access our Services through such an application). We are not responsible for what those parties do with your information, so you should make sure you trust the application and that it has a privacy policy that is acceptable to you.

**Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement Requests; Protection of Outreach's Rights**

We may disclose to third parties data stored in your Outreach account and information about you that we collect only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy and when we have a good faith belief that disclosure is reasonably necessary to (a) comply with a law, regulation, or compulsory legal request, such as to comply with a subpoena; (b) protect the safety of any person from death or serious bodily injury; (c) prevent fraud or abuse of Outreach or its users; or (d) to protect Outreach's rights. If we provide any data stored in your Outreach account to a law enforcement agency, we will remove Outreach's encryption from the information before providing it to law enforcement. However, Outreach will not be able to decrypt anything that you encrypted prior to uploading it to Outreach.

**Business Transfers**

If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, your information may be transferred as part of that transaction, but we will notify you (for example, via email, sign in notification, and/or a prominent notice on our website) if that happens or if your information otherwise becomes subject to a different privacy policy in lieu of this one. We will also notify you of choices you may have regarding the information. 

**Changing or Deleting Your Information**

Upon request Outreach will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your personal information. If you are a registered user, you may review, update, correct, or delete certain Personal Information provided in your registration or account profile by changing your account settings. If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our Service, you may update or delete it by making the change in your account settings, although (in some cases) we may retain copies of your information if required by law, to protect our rights, or if it is not technically reasonably feasible to remove it. For questions about your Personal Information on our Service, please contact [support@outreach.io](mailto:support@outreach.io) or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your inquiry within 30 days.

**Data Retention**

Our intention is to retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you with the Services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you Services, you may delete your account. We may retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements and rights, or if it is not technically reasonably feasible to remove it. Consistent with these requirements, we will try to delete your information quickly upon request. Please note, however, that there might be latency in deleting information from our servers and backed-up versions might exist after deletion. In addition, we do not delete information from our servers files if you have that information in common with other users.

**Choice/Opt-Out**

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page, or you can contact us at [support@outreach.io](mailto:support@outreach.io).

**Blogs**

Our website offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [support@outreach.io](mailto:support@outreach.io). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information. If this is the case, we will let you know and indicate why.

**Security**

Outreach stresses its privacy and security standards. Although no one can guarantee absolute security, we regularly re-evaluate our privacy and security policies in order to adapt to new challenges. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. We encrypt the most sensitive data that you store on Outreach using the AES-256 standard, which is the same encryption standard used by banks to secure customer data.

**Children**

Our Services are not directed to persons under 13. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with Personal Information without the parent's consent, he or she should contact us at [support@outreach.io](mailto:support@outreach.io). If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with Personal Information, we will take steps to delete such information from our files.

**Contacting Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [support@outreach.io](mailto:support@outreach.io), or at ComponentLab Inc., 1441 North 34th Street, Suite #100, Seattle, WA 98103.

**Changes to our Privacy Policy**

If we make a change to this privacy policy, we will provide you with notice (for example, by email, a sign-in notification, or some other means) prior to the change becoming effective. By continuing to use the Service after those changes become effective, you are agreeing to be bound by the revised Privacy and Security Policy; if you do not agree to the change, simply don't use the Service after the change is effective, in which case the change will not apply to you.

**Information Related to Data Collected through the Outreach Platform**

Outreach collects information under the direction of its Clients and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes.

**Choice**

Outreach acknowledges that you have the right to access your personal information. We collect information for our clients. If you are a customer of one of our Clients and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Clients that use our service, please contact the client that you interact with directly.

**Service Provider, Sub-Processors/Onward Transfer**

Outreach may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the provisions in this Policy regarding notice and choice, as well as the service agreements with our Clients.

**Access to Data Controlled by our Clients**

Outreach has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data, should direct his query to the Outreach's Client (the data controller). If the Client requests Outreach to remove the data, we will respond to the request within 30 business days.

**Data Retention**

Outreach will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Clients for as long as needed to provide services to our Client. Outreach will retain and use this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreement.
